So we've loaded in a pre-trained vgg16 model and frozen in our features parameters.
我们已经加载了预训练的 vgg16 模型并冻结了 features 参数
Our next task was to replace the last layer of
下个任务是替换模型的最后层级
the model so that instead of outputting a thousand classes,
以便针对 5 个花朵类别输出 5 个值
it outputted five values for our five flower classes.
而不是输出一千个类别
And this actually only takes a couple lines of code.
几行代码就能搞定
First, I need some information about the layer that I want to change,
首先 我需要获取要更改层级的信息
so I'm going to get it by name VGG classifier six.
我将用名称引用它 输入 vgg16.classifier[6]
From printing out our model architecture,
输出模型架构后发现
we know that the classifier contains
classifier 包含 3 个最终全连接层
three final fully-connected layers and six points to the last linear layers specifically.
6 指向最后的线性层级
Now I know I need to define a new linear layer that takes in as
现在我需要定义一个新的线性层级
input the same number of in features as the existing last layer,
输入数量和现有最后层级的输入特征数量一样
so I'm saving this number of inputs as N inputs.
我将这个输入数量另存为 n_inputs
Then, I'm defining a new last layer.
然后定义新的最后层级
I'm defining a linear layer as usual using our library.
使用 nn 库照常定义线性层级
I'm defining this layer to take those inputs
它的输入参数是 n_inputs
and produce as many outputs as we have classes.
生成的输出数量和类别数量一样
In this case, this length should be five.
这个长度应该为 5
Then again, I'm going to reference this last layer that I want to
引用我要替换的这个最后层级
replace and set it equal to this last layer that I just defined.
并将其设为刚刚定义的 last_ayer
This effectively replaces the old layer with the new layer.
这样就会将旧层级替换为新层级
Now, I should have a complete VGG 16 model
现在已经创建了完整的 VGG 16 模型
and I'll move this whole model to GPU if available.
如果 GPU 可用 则将整个模型移到 GPU 上
Finally, I'm just going to print out the number of out features in this layer,
最后输出这个层级的输出特征数量
just to check that I've done this correctly,
检查代码是否正确
and we can see that this produces five outputs which is exactly what I expect.
可以看到生成了 5 个输出 和预期的一样
The next detail here is to prepare this whole model for training.
接下来准备训练整个模型
I'm going to define loss and optimization functions as usual.
我将照常定义损失和优化函数
Only this time, you'll notice that in the optimizer,
但是这次在优化器中
I'm actually only passing in the parameters for the classifier.
我仅传入 classifier 的参数
These Classifier parameters are the only ones that I want to change during training.
在训练期间 我只想更改这些 classifier 参数
Then we get to the training loop.
然后是训练循环
I suggest training on GPU to speed this process up since these networks still
建议在 GPU 上训练以加快速度
contain a lot of parameters even in just the fully connected layers,
因为这个网络依然包含很多参数 即使全连接层也如此
and I'm only going to train for two epics.
我只训练 2 个周期
Since this model is pre-trained,
因为此模型已预训练
I should only need to train for a little while to tune
因此只需训练一小会儿
this model to our flower classification task.
就能让它适合处理花朵分类任务
In our training loop, I'm keeping track of the loss.
在训练循环里跟踪损失
My first step is moving any data to GPU and then zeroing out any accumulated gradients,
第一步是将所有数据移到 GPU 上 然后清理累积的梯度
and then pass in our image data into the VGG 16 network.
然后将图像数据传入 VGG 16 网络
This produces an output of class scores.
生成类别分数
Here I'm calculating the cross entropy loss and performing
在这里计算交叉熵损失
a single optimization step to change the weights of our network.
并执行一个优化步骤以更改网络权重
This step is only attached to the last few layers of our VGG model.
这一步仅附加到 VGG 模型的最后几个层级
The rest of the weights are frozen.
其他权重保持不变
And here, I'm just updating the training loss and printing it out every 20 batches.
在这里更新训练损失并每隔 20 个周期输出损失
I can see that the loss starts out small and decreases in a wiggly fashion.
可以看出 损失一开始很小 并且起伏不定地降低
Sometimes the loss moves up before it moves down again.
有时候损失会升高 然后再降低
But let's see how this performs after just two epics of training.
看看训练两个周期之后效果如何
Here, I'm iterating over our test data and I'm
在这里遍历测试数据
checking how our model does on our five classes.
检查模型在五个类别上的效果如何
After only two epics of training our model gets 74% accuracy on our images.
仅训练两个周期之后 模型的准确率就达到了 74%
Even though our dataset was small,
虽然数据集很小
I've managed to transfer the learnings from
但是我已成功地将 VGG 网络的经验
the VGG network to this very specific flower classification task.
迁移到了这个特定的花朵分类任务上
Let's take a look at what this looks like visually.
我们直观地看看效果
Here are some correctly and incorrectly classified images of flowers.
这些是分类正确和错误的花朵图像
Now, we know that transfer learning worked,
可以看到迁移学习成功了
because even though VGG was initially
虽然 VGG 一开始
trained to recognize a thousand different image types.
训练识别一千个不同的图像
The way it distinguished those images by finding
但是它通过寻找颜色和几何图案区分这些图像的经验
color and geometric patterns translated into distinguishing images of flowers as well.
也迁移到了区分花朵图像上
And you can see that some of the images this model
可以看出模型未能识别的某些图像
fails on are even difficult for us to identify.
对我们来说也很难识别
There are many models that you can try to implement transfer learning with,
你可以尝试对很多模型应用迁移学习
and you can even try training for a longer amount of time or fine-tuning entire models.
甚至可以训练更长的时间或微调整个模型
Take a look at the documentation on
请参阅可用的预训练模型的文档
available pre-trained models and experiment with creating your own applications.
并尝试自己创建应用场景
You could even extend this example to create something
你甚至可以拓展这个示例
like a weed versus flower application for gardeners.
并为园艺家创建种子与花朵模型
To me, the excitement is really in the variety of data that's out there.
现实中各式各样的数据提供了各种可能性
Data that you can train your models to learn from.
你可以利用这些数据训练模型
Let your imagination be your limit.
充分发挥想象力吧